Guide to the Chester Ittner Bliss Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Chester Ittner Bliss papers
1885-1998
1918-1976
MS 1165
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
43.54
(44 boxes)
The Chester Ittner Bliss Papers comprise writings and research materials, primarily in the field of biometry. The papers also include lecture notes, committee files, and printed matter.
Bliss, C. I. (Chester Ittner), 1899-1979
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Chester I. Bliss estate, 1979.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Chester Bliss was born in Springfield, Ohio, in 1899. B.A., Ohio State U., 1921; M.A., Columbia, 1922, Ph.D., 1926; asso. entomologist, U.S. Dept. of Agri., New Orleans, 1926-1929, entomologist, Mexico City, 1928, Whittier, Calif, 1930-1933; mem. Inst. Plant Protection, Leningrad, 1935-1937; biometrician Conn. Agr. Exptl. Station, New Haven, 1940-1971; biometrician Storrs, Conn. Expt. Sta., 1940-1953; lecturer at Yale, 1942-1967, 1972. Bliss died in 1979.
Scope and Contents
Writings and research materials, primarily in the field of biometry. The papers also include lecture notes, committee files, and printed matter.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged as received.
Biology; Biometry -- Study and teaching; Biometry; Mathematics; Science; Statistics; Biometricians; Bliss, C. I. (Chester Ittner), 1899-1979; Yale University -- Faculty
- Reprint bibliography of Chester I. Bliss, 1946-1970; 7 (Box 1)
- Reprints of works by Chester I. Bliss
  - Numbers 1-50, 1924-1945 (Box 1)
  - Numbers 51-87, 1946-1955 (Box 2)
  - Numbers 88-110, 1955-1964 (Box 3)
  - Numbers 111-132, 1964-1970 (Box 4)
- Photograph, Undated (Box 5)
- Reprints with data and charts, 1968 (Box 5)
- Reprint distribution information, 1938-1973 (Box 5)
- Chapter 21 (possibly for proposed Statistics in Biology, V. III), 1961-1971; 2 (Box 5)
- Bliss bibliography, 1964-1975 (Box 5)
- Outline of Biometry mimeo handouts, Undated; 2 (Box 5)
- Charts of planets, Undated (Box 41, Folder 92)
- Reprints by others, 1951-1969 (Box 6)
  - Anscombe, F. J., 1947-1962 (Box 6)
  - Armitage, P., 1950-1969 (Box 6)
  - Bartalett, M. S., 1953-1967; 2 (Box 6)
  - Berkson, J., 1947-1960; 2 (Box 6)
  - Bradley, R. A., 1952-1966; 2 (Box 6)
  - Cochran, W. G., 1939-1967 (Box 6)
  - Fisher, R. A., 1918-1950; 6 (Box 7)
  - Galstoff, P. S., 1885-1960 (Box 7)
  - Hazard, John N., 1936-1956; 2 (Box 7)
  - Nagasawa, S., 1949-1965; 2 (Box 8)
  - Yates, F., 1930-1949 (Box 8)
  - General
    - Blo-Bly, Undated (Box 8)
    - C-D, Undated (Box 8)
    - E-K, 1934-1976; 2 (Box 9)
    - L-S, 1955-1967; 2 (Box 9)
    - T, 1940-1962; 2 (Box 9)
    - W, 1944-1955; 2 (Box 9)
- Reprints from Paul-Erlich Institute, 1950-1954; 2 (Box 9)
- Bibliographic card file, Undated (Box 9A)
- Reprints from Paul-Erlich Institute and Program directories (old), 1954-1957 (Box 10)
- Schedules and maps, 1952-1954; 2 (Box 10)
- New York random sample poultry test, 1953-1955 (Box 10)
- Catalogues, 1962-1973 (Box 10)
- Correspondence, drafts, and data arranged according to reprint bibliography number
  - Numbers 7-84, 1934-1954 (Box 11)
  - Numbers 86-133, 1954-1970 (Box 12)
- Yale statistical laboratory, 1958-1961 (Box 13)
- Biometric Society (Eastern North American Region), 1960-1969 (Box 13)
- Biometrics, 1966-1968 (Box 13)
- Biometric Society circular, Undated (Box 13)
- American Statistical Association, 1971-1976 (Box 13)
- American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1968-1970 (Box 13)
- United States Pharmacopeia (USP) bioassays, 1954-1974 (Box 13)
- International Statistical Institute (ISI), 1966-1971 (Box 13)
- Medicare, Undated (Box 13)
- Council of Foreign Relations, 1957-1967 (Box 13)
- Handout, Christmas meeting, 1955 (Box 13)
- American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), 1968 (Box 13)
- Bioassay lectures, 1972 (Box 13)
- Correspondence abroad, 1953-1954 (Box 13)
- Correspondence file for continent, 1953-1954 (Box 13)
- Passport and trip to South America, 1955 (Box 13)
- Fulbright application, etc., 1952-1953 (Box 13)
- Sandusky, Ohio property, 1956-1963 (Box 13)
- General reports, correspondence, and staff lists, 1940-1970 (Box 13)
- Applications and vitae, 1938-1949 (Box 13)
- Correspondence file for England, 1953-1954 (Box 13)
- Correspondence file for continent, 1953-1954 (Box 13)
- Correspondence, 1973 (Box 13)
- Cambridge conference, 1962-1963 (Box 13)
- Finances, 1972-1973; 3 (Box 13)
- Correspondence, 1971-1972; 2 (Box 13)
- Animal vitamin assays, 1965-1967 (Box 14)
- Chapter 2, Statistical methods in bioassay, 1966 (Box 14)
- Correspondence, 1970 (Box 14)
- Corn borer counts, 1937-1942 (Box 14)
- Vitamin A, 1965-1966 (Box 14)
- Gyorgy book correspondence, 1963 (Box 14)
- Statistics of bioassay, vitamin assay examples, 1943-1947 (Box 14)
- Niacin, vitamin B6, pantothenic, folic acid, biotin, 1965-1967 (Box 14)
- Vitamin D, 1964-1966 (Box 14)
- Vitamin C, thiamine, riboflavin, 1965-1966 (Box 14)
- Vitamin K handouts, 1939 (Box 14)
- Analysis of Morrell's vitamin A assay, 1939 (Box 14)
- Vitamin K, Gyorgy book, Undated (Box 14)
- A course in Biometry for graduate students in Biology, Undated (Box 14)
- Chapters 2-4, exercises, 1935-1953 (Box 14)
- Chapters 5-6, examples, 1946 (Box 14)
- Chapters 7-8, exercises, Undated (Box 14)
- Chapters 9-11, exercises, 1948-1961 (Box 14)
- Biometric Society, 1963 (Box 14)
- Biometric Society: International, 1964 (Box 14)
- Biometric Society Council, 1965 (Box 14)
- Biometric Society, 1962 (Box 14)
- Biometric Society reference file, 1950-1959 (Box 14)
- ISI London, 1969 (Box 14)
- Outline of biometry (Botany 157), 1947 (Box 14)
- Pharmacology III, 1945 (Box 14)
- Periodic regression computer program, 1960 (Box 14)
- Course content of statistics for biologists, Biometric Society Report, 1955 (Box 14)
- Experiments on codling moth control, USDA; reports of statistical studies, 1929-1930 (Box 14)
- MSS: Standardization of entomological field experiments, 1926-1927 (Box 14)
- Entomological data and statistical distributions: outline and ms, 1937 (Box 14)
- Paper by Lubischew for biometrics, 1962 (Box 14)
- USDA project reports, 1928 (Box 14)
- Injection tests with oncopeltus, 1951-1956; 2 (Box 14)
- Determination of drug potency in man, 1952-1967 (Box 14)
- Horsfall lectures, 1956 (Box 14)
- Statistical lectures, 1956 (Box 14)
- Biological assays conference, 1949 (Box 14)
- Lectures, 1940-1942, 1962 (Box 15)
- Lectures at ISI seminars at Berne, 1949 (Box 15)
- Cycles, 1961-1962 (Box 15)
- Dr. John Haldi, Emory University School of Medicine, 1948 (Box 15)
- Agarol investigation, 1943-1944 (Box 15)
- Correspondence with Vahlteich, Peck, etc., 1941 (Box 15)
- Alexander Finlay, Charles Pfizer and Company, 1943 (Box 15)
- Experiment on tobacco smoke, 1946 (Box 15)
- Philip Morris and Co. report, 1944 (Box 15)
- Decompression sickness, University of Cincinnati, 1945 (Box 15)
- Official tests for the control of quality, 1951-1952 (Box 15)
- U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, 1941 (Box 15)
- U.S.D.A. corn borer projects, 1930-1942 (Box 15)
- Conference at Wallace Laboratories, 1966 (Box 15)
- Conferences at Ciba, Reserpine, 1954 (Box 15)
- Finances, 1964 (Box 15)
- Finances, 1963 (Box 15)
- Finances, 1962 (Box 15)
- Personal Correspondence, 1953 (Box 15)
- Insulin Assay, 1954 (Box 15)
- Parathyroid assay, 1954 (Box 15)
- Posterior pituitary assays, 1954-1955 (Box 15)
- Monte Carlo posterior pituitary study, Undated (Box 15)
- United States Pharmacopeia (U.S.P.) correspondence, 1950-1955 (Box 15)
- U.S.P. XV Statistical chapter, Undated (Box 15)
- Antibiotic assay, 1954 (Box 15)
- Corticotropin standard Armour data, 1954 (Box 15)
- Heparin assay, 1954-1955 (Box 15)
- Personal correspondence, 1942-1947 (Box 15)
- Family correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box 15)
- Correspondence A, 1946-1957 (Box 15)
- Correspondence Ba-Bl, 1939-1966 (Box 15)
- Correspondence Bo-By, 1941-1966 (Box 15)
- Correspondence Ca -Cl, 1941-1965 (Box 15)
- Correspondence Co-Cz, 1941-1965 (Box 15)
- Correspondence W.G. Cochran, 1940-1966 (Box 15)
- Correspondence Gertrude M. Cox, 1941-1966 (Box 15)
- Correspondence D, 1942-1963 (Box 16)
- Correspondence E, 1943-1963 (Box 16)
- Correspondence F, 1945-1960 (Box 16)
- Correspondence D.J. Finney, 1943-1963 (Box 16)
- Correspondence Ronald A. Fisher, 1941-1960 (Box 16)
- Correspondence G, 1941-1965 (Box 16)
- Correspondence H, 1941-1965 (Box 16)
- Correspondence I, 1941-1966 (Box 16)
- Correspondence J, 1950-1965 (Box 16)
- Correspondence K, 1955-1960 (Box 16)
- Correspondence L, 1946-1960 (Box 16)
- Correspondence Ma-Me, 1944-1964 (Box 16)
- Correspondence McGraw-Hill, 1957-1961 (Box 16)
- Correspondence Mi-My, 1942-1965 (Box 16)
- Correspondence Miller, Lloyd, 1941-1957 (Box 16)
- Correspondence N, 1941-1966 (Box 16)
- Correspondence, Nagasawa, Sumio, 1955-1957 (Box 16)
- Correspondence National Science Foundation, 1954-1957 (Box 16)
- Correspondence O, 1942-1962 (Box 16)
- Correspondence Pa-Pn, 1942-1964 (Box 16)
- Correspondence Po-Py, 1947-1965 (Box 16)
- Correspondence R, 1941-1959 (Box 16)
- Correspondence Sa-Sm, 1943-1965 (Box 16)
- Correspondence Sn-Sy, 1941-1956 (Box 16)
- Correspondence T, 1941-1965 (Box 16)
- Correspondence U, 1957 (Box 16)
- Correspondence V, 1942-1965 (Box 16)
- Correspondence W, 1942-1965 (Box 16)
- Correspondence Y, 1941-1965 (Box 16)
- Correspondence Z, 1956-1963 (Box 16)
- Reprint requests, 1960-1962 (Box 16)
- Correspondence, 1967 (Box 16)
- General finances, 1954-1963 (Box 16)
- AAAS, 1969-1970 (Box 16)
- Reference tables 1-10, 1941-1959 (Box 17)
- Reference tables 11-13, 1958-1959 (Box 17)
- Reference tables 14-22, 1963-1964 (Box 17)
- Reference tables 34-, 1948-1969 (Box 17)
- Vol. II contents, figures, analysis of growth data, Undated (Box 17)
- Outline of biometry notes, 1950-1954 (Box 17)
- Vol. II title page, contents, reference tables, captions, 1969-1970 (Box 17)
- Reference tables 23-33, 1954 (Box 17)
- Corrections for book: reader's memos, 1963-1965 (Box 17)
- Reference table xerox, Undated (Box 17)
- Reference tables, Undated (Box 17)
- Anova MSS, 1968 (Box 17)
- Anova examples, 1951-1968 (Box 17)
- Permissions glossary, 1965 (Box 17)
- Chapter 25 duplicated, 1937-1967 (Box 17)
- Radio immuno assays (RIA), 1968 (Box 17)
- Correspondence with McGraw-Hill, 1955-1965 (Box 17)
- Analysis of Growth Data, 1939-1949 (Box 17)
- Secretary at the station, 1965-1970 (Box 18)
- HLH assay, K=16, Undated (Box 18)
- RIA MSS, 1967 (Box 18)
  - Endocrine statistics notes, 1967 (Box 18)
- RIA -revised, 1968 (Box 18)
- RIA handouts, Undated (Box 18)
- Other RIA, 1968 (Box 18)
- RIA Rodbard et al, 1968-1969 (Box 18)
- RIA insulin assay, 1966-1968 (Box 18)
- Endocrine research conference, 1966-1969 (Box 18)
- Experiments on reaction time anthropods, 1919-1934 (Box 18)
- IX. size factor: text, 1935 (Box 18)
- Statistics for medical students, 1942-1944 (Box 18)
- Range rejection criterion, masters and copies, Undated (Box 18)
- Some statistical aspects of synergism, 1956-1959 (Box 18)
- Synergism, Undated (Box 18)
- USP-parathyroid assay, 1940-1941 (Box 18)
- Virus assays-J.W. Fisher, 1947 (Box 18)
- Chicken tumor assay-Bryan, 1946 (Box 18)
- Dr. Werner L. Lipschitz, 1943-1944 (Box 18)
- Corticotropin standard other laboratories, 1954 (Box 18)
- Corticotropin assay, 1954 (Box 18)
- Data from Whitlock on time-mortality curves, 1938-1941 (Box 18)
- Reaction time in mammals, 1942 (Box 18)
- Tests on goldfish-Gersdoff, 1937 (Box 18)
- Test assay of Oestrone, 1941 (Box 18)
- Microbiological assays from Withner, 1948 (Box 18)
- Riboflavin assay, response x log dose, Undated (Box 18)
- Effects of the anesthetic and the rate of injection of digitalis upon its lethal dose in cats, 1943-1946 (Box 18)
- Toxicity of cardiac glycocides to cats as tested by K.K. Chen, 1941-1942 (Box 18)
- U.S.P. reference digitalis calculations, 1944-1945 (Box 18)
- Digitalis assay, 1942 (Box 18)
- Digitoxin in cats-K.K. Chen, 1953-1954 (Box 18)
- Analysis of biological counts, 1937-1951 (Box 18)
- Vick data, 1971 (Box 18)
- Correspondence, 1938-1954 (Box 18)
- U.S.P. digitalis study on reference standard, 1946 (Box 19)
- Animal distribution, 1952-1954 (Box 19)
- Leafhopper counts, 1924-1927 (Box 19)
- Spruce budworm - Waters, Undated (Box 19)
- Leptinotarsa - Beall, Undated (Box 19)
- Stability of negative binomial, 1936-1949 (Box 19)
- Red mite - Garman, 1941-1952 (Box 19)
- Soil insect counts, 1954 (Box 19)
- Plant distributions, Undated (Box 19)
- Nagasawa - data and letters, 1957-1969 (Box 19)
- World Health Organization - expert committee on biological standardization, 1969 (Box 19)
- Organic acids, Undated (Box 19)
- Bioassay of insecticides, 1957-1959 (Box 19)
- Soybean multivariate calculations in statistics lab, 1942-1959 (Box 19)
- Particle size and toxicity, 1949 (Box 19)
- Precision of spectographic and chemical analyses of alfalfa - Mathis, 1951-1956 (Box 19)
- Neg. Bin. examples - Montreal, 1956 (Box 19)
- Dosage mortality curves from counts of survivors, 1947 (Box 19)
- Hand-outs for Fred Smith's course at U. Michigan, Undated (Box 19)
- Storrs station - letters, 1941-1950 (Box 19)
- Projects for home economics, 1947 (Box 19)
- Projects for entomology, 1940 (Box 19)
- Yale University, 1944-1948 (Box 19)
- Statistical methods in medicine, 1959 (Box 19)
- Outline - reprint permissions, copyright, 1951-1955 (Box 19)
- Handouts at Vanderbilt U., 1956 (Box 19)
- Training of statisticians, 1945-1952 (Box 19)
- Summer course at Raleigh, N.C., 1941 (Box 19)
- Summer session at Raleigh, 1946 (Box 19)
- National Reseearch Council - committee on applied mathematical statistics, 1947-1957 (Box 19)
- Correspondence, 1968 (Box 19)
- Correspondence, 1969 (Box 19)
- Collaborative analgesic experiments correspondence, 1947-1956 (Box 19)
- Analgesic Study: New York U., 1947 (Box 19)
- Analgesic study :Wellcome Laboratories, 1947 (Box 19)
- Analgesic study: Hoffmann LaRoche, 1947 (Box 19)
- Analgesic Study: Winthrop, 1947 (Box 19)
- Analgesic Study: University of Iowa, 1947 (Box 19)
- Rat pain response - Wyeth, 1945-1946 (Box 19)
- Analgesic Study: Yale, 1947 (Box 19)
- Assay of biologicals - Bethesda, 1931-1944 (Box 19)
- Memos and notes on biological assay, 1946-1948 (Box 19)
- USP Vitamin D assay, 1951-1953 (Box 19)
- Notes on assay of vitamin D in chicks, 1943-1948 (Box 19)
- Vitamin D. assay, 1953-1955 (Box 19)
- Tubocurarine assay, 1954 (Box 19)
- Analysis of vasopressin, 1954-1955 (Box 19)
- Vasopressin assay, 1954-1955 (Box 19)
- The measurement of biological potency - diagrams, photographs, Undated (Box 19)
- Nicotinic acid assay response and log dose, 1953 (Box 19)
- Vitamin D assay with creeper chicks, 1942 (Box 19)
- Vitamin A Assays, 1938-1948 (Box 19)
- Liver storage assay vitamin A, 1947 (Box 19)
- Gyorgy book-vitamin E, 1940-1948 (Box 20)
- Vitamin E, 1965-1967 (Box 20)
- Antidiuretic assay of posterior pituitary calculations and reports, 1938-1939 (Box 20)
- U.S.P. - epinephrine, 1952 (Box 20)
- Microbiological assays, 1945-1954 (Box 20)
- Vitamin B 12 - Nov. and Dec. data, 1954-1955 (Box 20)
- New analysis B 12 data, 1954 (Box 20)
- USP vitamin B 12 assay, 1954-1955 (Box 20)
- Vitamin K calculations, 1966-1967 (Box 20)
- Vitamin K paper, 1966-1967 (Box 20)
- Response criteria for vitamin K MSS, 1967-1968 (Box 20)
- Metrozol experiments, 1950-1963 (Box 20)
- Insulin assay: charts, symmetrical pairs, data, 1947 (Box 20)
- Relation of bleeding time to insulin assay - Mark's data, 1939 (Box 20)
- USP insulin assay, 1954 (Box 20)
- Insulin - Lacey, 1945-1946 (Box 20)
- Rabbit assay of insulin: data from sharp and Dohme and Toronto Laboratory, 1942 (Box 20)
- Insulin mouse slopes, 1935 (Box 20)
- Reaction time of mice to insulin - calculations, 1935 (Box 20)
- Reaction time of mice to insulin, original protocols, 1935 (Box 20)
- Working angles, 1967-1968 (Box 20)
- Wright's paper and critique, 1941 (Box 20)
- U.S.P. collaborative digitalis study using frogs by Lloyd C. Miller, MSS, 1936-1944 (Box 20)
- Dawson's data on cats, 1938 (Box 20)
- Penicillin, 1946 (Box 20)
- Penicillin - Pfizer turbidimetric assay data and manuscript, 1943 (Box 20)
- Penicillin assays from Wintrhop, 1944 (Box 20)
- Mysidium data, analysis with Bliss, 1958-1959 (Box 20)
- U.S.P. penicillin report with calculations, 1944 (Box 20)
- U.S.P. collaborative penicillin assay analysis for each laboratory, 1944 (Box 20)
- Penicillin turbidimetric assays U.S.P. collaborative, 1944 (Box 20)
- Penicillin - Pfizer data; Oxford or Plate assays, 1943 (Box 20)
- Rectangular hyperbola handouts, Undated (Box 20)
- Dosage - response curves for ergometrine and vitamin D, 1939-1941 (Box 20)
- Review on "Outline of Biometry" by H. Fairfield Smith, 1955 (Box 20)
- Handouts at Atlantic City, Undated (Box 20)
- Periodic regression handouts, Undated (Box 20)
- Lecture handouts, 1952 (Box 20)
- Regression when the assays have different variances, Undated (Box 20)
- Leafhopper nymphs: rates of disappearance, miscellaneous, 1931 (Box 21)
- Leafhopper: analysis of instar records by Ackerman, 1927-1929 (Box 21)
- Leafhopper nymphs instar calculations not used in final analysis, 1922-1928 (Box 21)
- Leafhopper nymphs insectary and regional temperature records, 1923-1928 (Box 21)
- Thermograph sheets, 1923-1924 (Box 21)
- 400 field counts, 1948-1949 (Box 21)
- Test of negative binomial, 1951 (Box 21)
- 225 field counts, Undated (Box 21)
- Counts with other stains, Undated (Box 21)
- Center/Border comparisons, Undated (Box 21)
- Homogeneity within and between files, Undated (Box 21)
- Poisson tests on 100-field counts, Undated (Box 21)
- 100 field counts - 2-4 film milks, Undated (Box 21)
- 100 field counts - 10 film milks, Undated (Box 21)
- Tests on border effect, 1930 (Box 21)
- Sequential counts, Undated (Box 21)
- Relation between problem and level of variation, Undated (Box 21)
- Drosophila - HCN, Undated (Box 21)
- Original data on fumigation drosophila with HCN, Undated (Box 21)
- Fumigation experiments with drosophila, 1935 (Box 21)
- Leafhopper nymphs MSS, Undated (Box 21)
- Effects of temperature upon toxicity of HCN to red scales, 1932 (Box 21)
- Effect of temperature on prepupal development of drosophila, 1926 (Box 21)
- Biological data on drosophila: oviposition, puparial sages, diurnal change in emergence, 1930 (Box 21)
- Relation between problem and level of variation: outline, manuscript, Undated (Box 21)
- The control of heterogeneity: outline, manuscript, notes, 1937 (Box 21)
- Physiology of citrus leaves, 1926-30 (Box 21)
- Life history - grape leafhopper, 1923 (Box 21)
- Leafhoppers: data from Jewett in Kentucky, 1921-1922 (Box 21)
- Velocity constants - first manuscript, 1923-1924 (Box 21)
- Temperature characteristics for leafhopper eggs, 1923-1925 (Box 21)
- Grape leafhopper, field occurence, 1922-1924 (Box 21)
- Oviposition rate of grape leafhopper, 1927 (Box 21)
- Leafhopper eggs - curvilinear regression calculations, 1926-1927 (Box 21)
- Leafhopper eggs - all species, data, calculations, 1922-1924 (Box 21)
- Concentration-time experiments with HCN on red scale, 1932 (Box 21)
- Field fumigations of red scale on lemons, Francis Street grove, Corona, 1931 (Box 21)
- Field fumigation of red scale on lemons, Proud grove, 1931-1932 (Box 21)
- Laboratory fumigations of red scale with HCN, various groves, 1932 (Box 21)
- Field fumigations of red scale on lemons, College grove, Whittier, 1931-1932 (Box 21)
- Chemical analyses of HCN concentration, 1924 (Box 21)
- Cyanide and red scale programs; references on fumigants, notes, etc., 1927-1928 (Box 21)
- Grape leafhopper maps, photos, Undated (Box 21)
- Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 22)
- Soviet Union, 1962 (Box 22)
- Comparison of slopes with a common intercept. Chapter 22, Undated (Box 22)
- Toxicity of oil emulsions to camphor scale, Undated (Box 22)
- Laboratory fumigations, HCN on red scale, Proud grove, 1931-1932 (Box 22)
- Response of red scale to HCN in relation to biological factors: outlines, correspondence, 1931-1935, 1953 (Box 22)
- Comparison of toxicity of HCN to resistant and non-resistant red scale, 1935-1940 (Box 22)
- Rotenone and alternates: vegetable insects, 1942 (Box 22)
- Box fumigation of aphids, 1927 (Box 22)
- Experiments in the Peet-Grady chamber, 1932-1934 (Box 22)
- Insecticide Tests: duplicate data and correspondence, 1942 (Box 22)
- Arsenicals and alternates: cotton, 1943 (Box 22)
- Arsenicals and alternates: fruit insects, 1942-1943 (Box 22)
- Field cage experiment on alfalfa snout beetle, 1942 (Box 22)
- Cage tests, 1935 (Box 22)
- Copper and alternates, 1942 (Box 22)
- Celery sprays, G.R. Townsend, Florida, 1942 (Box 22)
- February 14 conference, notes and oultines, 1943 (Box 22)
- Japanese beetles larvae, 1941 (Box 22)
- Ecology Symposium, 1969 (Box 22)
- Lectures in Japan, 1967 (Box 22)
- Notes on assay of vitamin D in rats, 1948-1949 (Box 22)
- Sixth Biometric Society conference, 1967 (Box 22)
- Correspondence re: tour, 1967 (Box 22)
- New York Academy of Science conference, 1968 (Box 22)
- ENAR meeting, 1968 (Box 22)
- AAAS - Dallas, 1968 (Box 22)
- Symposium on drug evaluation, Florida, 1968 (Box 22)
- International Biological Program, 1968-1969 (Box 22)
- Biometric Symposium, 1965-1967 (Box 22)
- Seventh International Biometric Conference, 1967-1969 (Box 22)
- Talk banquet, 1964 (Box 22)
- I.S.I session - Sydney Chapters 18-20, 1967; 2 (Box 22)
- Visit of R.A. Fisher, 1957-1958 (Box 22)
- Tables I - VI, Undated (Box 22)
- Table of logits and antilogits, Undated (Box 22)
- Fitting the rectangular hyberbola, xerox copy, 1965-1966 (Box 22)
- Data analysis and behavioral science, J.W. Turkey, 1966; 2 (Box 22)
- Bulletins, 1932-1942 (Box 22)
- Project: Fruit and shade tree insects, 1933 (Box 22)
- Box Fumigation Tests with HCN, Undated (Box 22)
- Gyorgy book, 1950 (Box 23)
  - Vitamin D, 1947-1949 (Box 23)
  - Vitamin A, 1949 (Box 23)
  - Riboflavin, 1948 (Box 23)
  - Thiamine - B 1, 1939-1947 (Box 23)
  - Ascorbic acid, 1948 (Box 23)
  - Vitamin B12, 1949 (Box 23)
  - Folic acid, 1948 (Box 23)
  - Other vitamins, 1948 (Box 23)
  - Other chapters, 1947 (Box 23)
  - Animal assays, 1946 (Box 23)
  - Vitamin K, 1939-1949 (Box 23)
  - Niacin, Undated (Box 23)
  - Biotin, 1948 (Box 23)
  - Pantothenic acid, Undated (Box 23)
  - Pyridoxine, 1948 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1951 (Box 23)
- Sequential curves and tests, Undated (Box 23)
- Finances, 1965 (Box 23)
- Yale alcohol studies, 1956 (Box 23)
- General models in biology, Undated (Box 23)
- Memo of fertilizer report, 1964 (Box 23)
- Fertilizer bulletin, 1965 (Box 23)
- Statistical relations in fertilizer inspection, 1959-1963 (Box 23)
- Income, 1966 (Box 22)
- Finances, 1967 (Box 23)
- Notes on asssay of Vitamin B12, 1952-1955 (Box 23)
- Microbial assay MSS, 1954-1955 (Box 23)
- Calcium pantothenate, 1954 (Box 23)
- U.S.P. vitamin advisory board, 1953-1954 (Box 23)
- Miscellaneous symposia printed matter, 1940-1967; 2 (Box 24)
- Discrete distribution symposium, I, 1963; 2 (Box 24)
- Discrete distribution symposium, II, 1963; 2 (Box 24)
- ISI and IMS Symposia, 1963; 2 (Box 24)
- Cambridge Biometric Conference, I, 1963 (Box 24)
- Cambridge Biometric Conference, II, 1963 (Box 24)
- Notebook from ISI symposium, 1967 (Box 25)
- USDA publication #366, 1941 (Box 25)
- Paper by J. Tripod, Undated (Box 25)
- Paper by Leopold Martin, Undated (Box 25)
- Chapter 29, Undated (Box 25)
- Chapter 27, Undated (Box 25)
- Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station record of the years, 1968-1970 (Box 25)
- USAF bulletins, 1960-1962 (Box 25)
- Tables For Use With Binomial Samples, 1956 (Box 25)
- Poisson's Exponential Binomial Limit, 1942 (Box 25)
- Reference tables from biometrika, 1943 (Box 25)
- Statistics for Biologists, Chapters 25-28, Undated (Box 25)
- Statistics for Biologists, Chapter 26, Undated (Box 25)
- Animal Nutrition Research, 1964-1975 (Box 25)